Finding Aid for Sari Khoury Papers 1960-1999
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Sari Khoury Papers 1960-19991970-1990
Khoury, Sari, 1941-1997.
1 linear ft.
Sari Khoury was a Palestinian-American artist and professor at Central Michigan University. The collection consists primarily of exhibition materials of his shows, and documents related to his work as a professor at CMU.
03153 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Suheila Khoury (donor no. 9356 ) in July 2003.
The collection is open for research.
Sari Khoury was born on March 13, 1941 in Jerusalem, Palestine. As a result of continuing war, in 1948 his family moved to Ramallah. They lived there until 1959 when they emigrated to the United States, to pursue greater educational opportunity for Sari and his siblings. Sari received his Bachelor of Fine Art from Ohio Wesleyan University in 1963 and his Masters of Fine Art from Cranbrook Academy of Art in 1965. He taught at Berea College in Berea, Kentucky from 1965-1967. Sari Khoury was hired as an assistant art professor at Central Michigan University in 1967 and then received tenure in 1972. He was eventually promoted to department chair and continued to teach at CMU until shortly before his death in 1997 from cancer. During his life Sari Khoury was a prolific painter, usually in the non-figurative style, and displayed his paintings in galleries in Europe, Japan, and the United States. He was very involved with Arab-American issues, and participated in many exhibitions and festivals celebrating Arab artists.
The Sari Khoury collection consists primarily of materials related to Khoury's work as a painter and teacher at Central Michigan University. It is divided into four series: Biographical, Exhibitions, Photographs, and Topical Files.
Subjects:
Khoury, Sari, 1941-1997.; Arab Americans--Michigan.; Artists--Michigan.; Central Michigan University--Faculty.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Khoury, Sari, 1941-1997.; Artists--Michigan.; Arab Americans--Michigan.
Genre/Form:
Photographs.
- Biographical
  The Biographical series spans from 1966-1999 and contains newspapers and newsletters, coursework, awards, resumes, and materials collected by his wife, Suheila, after Sari Khoury's death. They are arranged chronologically.
  - Newspapers and newsletters, 1966-1994 (Box 1)
  - Coursework, 1961-1966 (Box 1)
  - Awards, 1980-1992 (Box 1)
  - Resumes and CVs, 1974-1992 (Box 1)
  - After death, 1997-1999 (Box 1)
- Exhibitions
  The Exhibitions series spans from 1966-1996 and contains flyers, catalogues, letters, and entry forms related to Sari Khoury's art exhibitions.
  - 1966-1984 (Box 1)
  - 1985-1996 (Box 1)
- Photographs
  The Photographs series contains one slide and photographs of Sari Khoury and his artwork.
  - Portraits and informal photographs of SK in studio and at exhibitions (Box 1)
- Topical Files
  The Topical Files series contains materials relating to Sari Khoury's involvement with Arab/Middle-East issues, his work at CMU and Berea College, records of sabbatical work and grant proposals, and correspondences.
  - Arab related materials, 1970-1994 (Box 1)
  - Berea College, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Sabbatical work and grant proposals, 1972-1993 (Box 1)
  - Central Michigan University, 1967-1996 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 1)